CAREER OBJECTIVE

Emerging data science professional searching for employment opportunities in a dynamic organization learning from the industry experts. My passions are microeconomics, game theory, machine learning, and functions. Ultimately, I strive to add value and contribute to the success to any company or organization of which I am a member.

CONTACT

PHONE:

401-743-9557

EMAIL:

jwilliams 388@icloud.com

WEBSITE:

https://jw388743.github.io

SOFT SKILLS

- Creative & Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Interpersonal Skills
- Judgement

HARD SKILLS

- Data Exploration
- Data Cleaning/Preparation
- Data Visualization
- Hypothesis Testing
- Statistical Modeling
- Time-Series Analysis
- Machine Learning
- Web Scraping
- Functional Programming
- R Package Development
- R Shiny
- Version Control

JAMES WILLIAMS

EDUCATION

Boston College

May 2019 - Aug. 2020

Master of Science in Applied Economics

GPA: 3.9

Coursework: Behavioral Economics, Machine Learning, Forecasting, Econometrics

Suffolk University

Aug. 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Arts in Economics

GPA: 3.77 (cum laude)

Economics Department Award for Academic Excellence

Relevant Coursework: Statistics, Calculus, Econometrics, Forecasting, Game Theory

WORK EXPERIENCE

Forrester Research

Sept. 2020 - Present

Data Science Associate, CX Index

- Automate reports and deliverables by developing R packages.
- Acted as a primary maintainer of six R packages used in automation processes.
- Execute custom client analysis for analyst's presentations.
- Develop automation tools to solve data pipeline inefficiencies.
- Developed and launched a Shiny app for internal company use.
- Work directly with analysts and data scientists to solve business problems.
- Contribute to research reports by providing insights from data analysis.
- Lead presentations with clients to answer questions about analyses conducted.

Forrester Research

Feb. 2020 - Sept. 2020

Data Science Intern, CX Index
Automate reports and deliverables by developing R packages.

- Assisted as a maintainer of six R packages used in automation processes.
- Learned version control and package development best practices.

Concord Wealth Management

May 2019 - Feb. 2020

Operations Administrative Associate

- Track expenses create expense reports, and cost controlling.
- Created and maintained presentations for leaders in the office.
- Created and maintained weekly trackers for office leader's KPIs.

TOOLS

